

Patrick Michl

Data Scientist | Al Engineer



PERSONAL

Contact Floringasse 5, 69117 Heidelberg, DE

Phone: +49 177 85 44 151 Email: patrick.michl@gmail.com

Legal POB/Date-: 93309 Kelheim, DE at 05/19/1982

Nationality: German Marital status: Single

Online Professional profile: LinkedIn ☑

Research profile: ORCid @ | Heidelberg University @

Software development: GitHub & Blog/Talks: Frootlab & | SlideShare &

Certificates: Credly ☑ | Coursera ☑ | Scrum.org ☑



ABOUT

I spent the most part of my professional and educational lifetime by shaping my experience and expertise in AI, machine learning, software development and network technologies. During this process I gained domain specific insights into different industries comprising manufacturing (engineering, shop floor and office) as well as finance and pharma (research). I identify myself as a passionate mathematician, obsessive software developer and convinced AI enthusiast.



EDUCATION

Heidelberg, 2006 - 2018

Mathematics Diploma: Grade 1.4 / GPA 3.6, with specialization in statistics/machine learning and differential geometry. Subsidiary subjects: Theoretical physics, applied computer sciences and systems biology. Research in systems biology with honored diploma thesis: *Principal Manifold based Correlation Analysis* ☑

Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule

Regensburg, 2003 - 2006

Applied mathematics with specialization in graph theory, optimization and operations-research. Subsidiary subject: Economics. Internship Semester: Development and implementation of a graph-based optimization algorithm for multiple source machine translation $\@Box{\@Box}$



LANGUAGES

German: Native | English: Fluent | French: Basic | Irish: Basic



EXPERIENCE

Mannheim, 03/2020 - Present

Data Scientist: Al driven shop floor automation, business analytics, database development, predictive maintenance, robotic process automation, IT project management, digitalization projects

Heidelberg, 03/2018 - 02/2020

Freelance Data Scientist: Data Warehousing and cloud computing projects in the Rhine-Neckar metropolitan region. Remote planning and implementation of data analysis- and digitalization projects

Frootlab Smart Analytics &

Heidelberg, 05/2016 - Present

Founder, software architect and consultant for data science collaboration projects between industry-, public sector- and academic teams, using the "Vivid Code" cloud collaboration framework $\ensuremath{\mathbb{Z}}$

06/2008 - 02/2014, *Institute for Mathematics* ☑ Systemadministrator: Unix-Administration and network programming

05/2012 - 07/2012, Institute for Molecular Biotechnology ♂ Research Assistant: Deep learning based gene expression analysis

10/2008 - 03/2009, Institute for Computer Sciences

T

Lecture Assistant: Applied CS at software engineering research group

Heidelberg, 12/2012 - 01/2014

Research Assistant: Research in deep-learning-based gene regulation analysis with application to breast cancer and glioblastoma multiforme at network modeling research group

National Chamber of Commerce and Industry Regenstauf, 10/2011 - 09/2012

Freelance Technical Writer: Authoring of the textbook "Network Technology Fundamentals" as part of the vocational education program of electrical engineers in Germany



SKILLS

Machine Learning | Statistics | AI | Data Visualization and Presentation Process Mining | Predictive Maintenance | Network Technologies Business Analytics | Statistical Programming (Python, R, SAS, Octave) Database Programming and -Design (SQL, noSQL, VFP, VBA, UML) Web & Cloud (PHP, JS, REST, Azure, IBM-Cloud, Snowflake, Spark) IT Project Management (Classic, Scrum) | Hardware Programming (C/C++, CANoe, CAPL, SPS) | Administration (Linux, Microsoft 365)